Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello RG.007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series III: Publications and Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Publications and Reports (#3-#326, M, N)
    - #274 - Bugliarello, G., "A New Trivium and Quadrivium," (excerpt), American Scientist, Vol. 90, No. 4, July-August 2002., 2002 July-August (Box 30, Folder 70)
    - #275 - Bugliarello, G., "Machines, Modifications of Nature, and Engineering Ethics," The Bridge, Vol. 32, No. 3, Fall 2002., 2002 Fall (Box 30, Folder 71)
    - #276 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Knowledge Parks," in Toward a New Agenda: Business, Social and Urban Development Impacts, XIX IASP World Conference on Science and Technology Parks, Quebec, Canada, September 3-6, 2002., 2002 September (Box 30, Folder 72)
    - #277 - Bugliarello, G., "The Expanding Frontiers of Engineering," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 32, No. 4, Winter 2002., 2002 Winter (Box 30, Folder 73)
    - #278 - Bugliarello, G., "A New Trivium and Quadrivium," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, April 2003., 2003 April (Box 30, Folder 74)
    - #279 - Bugliarello, G., "Energy, Geopolitics, Sustainability, and Engineering," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 33, No. 2, Summer 2003., 2003 Summer (Box 30, Folder 75)
    - #280 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering Ethics: The Ethics of the Linkage Between Engineering and Biology," The Experiences and Challenges of Science and Ethics, The National Academies Press, 2003. (Box 30, Folder 76)
    - #281 - Bugliarello, G., "Message from the Foreign Secretary," The Bridge, Vol. 33, No. 3, Fall 2003., 2003 Fall (Box 30, Folder 77)
    - #282 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban versus Non-Urban Knowledge Parks," Research Park Forum, Research Park Reports, Vol. 1, No. 2, October 2003., 2003 October (Box 30, Folder 78)
    - #283 - Bugliarello, G., "The Ongoing Expansion of Frontiers of Engineering," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 33, No. 4, Winter 2003., 2003 Winter (Box 30, Folder 79)
    - #284 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Security in Perspective," Technology in Society, Vol. 25, No. 4, pp. 499- 507, November 2003, 2003 November (Box 30, Folder 80)
    - #285 - Bugliarello, G., "Large Urban Concentrations: A New Phenomenon," Earth Science in the City: A Reader, Heiken, G., R. Fakundiny and J. Sutter (eds.), American Geophysical Union, Washington, DC, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 81)
    - #286 - Bugliarello, G., "Il Biosoma," La Nuova Scienza- La Società Infobiologica, Libri Scheiwiller, Milan, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 82)
    - #287 - Bugliarello, G., "Metrotech: Un Parque Urbano del Conocimiento en New York," Historia y Modernidad, Fundación Ferrol Metrópoli, Ferrol, Spain, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 83)
    - #288 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Security and September 11, 2001, in New York City: Projection of Threats onto a City as a Target and Measures to Avert Them or Minimize Their Impact," Terrorism - Reducing Vulnerabilities and Improving Responses - U.S.-Russian Workshop Proceedings, The National Academies Press, Washington, D.C., 2004 (Box 30, Folder 84)
    - #289 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering, Foreign Policy, and Global Challenges," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 34, No. 2, Summer 2004, 2004 Summer (Box 30, Folder 85)
    - #290 - Bugliarello, G., "Biosoma Engineering and the Advancement of Humankind," Proceedings of the 10th Anniversary Celebration of the Chinese Academy Engineering, China, June 2004, 2004 June (Box 30, Folder 86)
    - #291 - Bugliarello, G., "The Biotechnology Revolution," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 34, No. 3, Fall 2004, 2004 Fall (Box 30, Folder 87)
    - #293 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Knowledge Parks, Knowledge Cities and Urban Sustainability," International Journal of Technology Management, Vol. 28, Nos. 3/4/5/6, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 88)
    - #294 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Security in the United States: An Overview," Technology in Society, Vol. 27, pp. 287 - 293, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 89)
    - #295 - Bugliarello, G., "Systems Challenges on a Global Scale," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 35, No. 2, Summer 2005, 2005 Summer (Box 30, Folder 90)
    - #296 - Bugliarello, G., "Globalization and Engineering," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 35, No. 3, Fall 2005, 2005 Fall (Box 30, Folder 91)
    - #298 – Bugliarello, G., "The Aftermath of Katrina," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 36, No. 1, Spring 2006, 2006 Spring (Box 30, Folder 92)
    - #299 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Sustainability: Dilemmas, Challenges and Paradigms," Technology In Society, Vol. 28, pp. 19 - 26, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 93)
    - #300 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Sustainability: Science, Technology, and Policies," Journal of Urban Technology, Vol. 11, 2004, pp. 1-11. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - #301 – Bugliarello, G., "JUT Note: Technology and Bodegas," Journal of Urban Technology, Vol. 13, No. 2, 2006, pp. 113-122. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - #302 – Bugliarello, G., "Urban Sustainability," Hanlim Distinguished Lecture, Korean Academy of Science and Technology, November 3, 2006, 2006 November 3 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - #303 – Bugliarello, G., "Critical Integration and Coordination Issues in Urban Security," in Countering Urban Terrorism in Russia and the United States, Proceedings of a Workshop, Committee on Counterterrorism Challenges for Russia and the United States, The National Academies Press, Washington, DC, 2006. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - #304 – Bugliarello, G., "Science, Technology and Society—the Tightening Circle," Materials Science and Technology (MS&T) 2006: Fundamentals and Characterizations: Volume I, Proceedings of MS&T06 Lectures, 2006. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - #304a - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Sustainability: an Introductory Interdisciplinary Course in the Engineering Curriculum," in Congress Proceedings, UNESCO International Centre for Engineering Education (UICEE) 5th Global Congress on Engineering Education in collaboration with Polytechnic University (Zenon J. Pudlowski, ed.), UICEE, 2006. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - #305 – Bugliarello, G., "The Biosoma Paradigm and Environmental Engineering," Environmental Engineering Science, Vol. 24, No. 3, 2007. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - #306 – Bugliarello, G., "Using Technology to Enhance the Economic Efficiency of Small Retail Establishments," Applied Research in Economic Development, Vol. 4, No. 1, 2007. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - #307 – Bugliarello, G., "Biomedical Engineering Ethics and Cultural Specificity," International Journal of Medical Implants and Devices, Vol. 2, No. 1, 2007, pp. 13-39. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - #308 – Bugliarello, G., "The Engineering Challenges of Urban Sustainability," Journal of Urban Technology, Vol. 15, No. 1, 2008, pp. 53-83. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - #309 – Bugliarello, G., "Infrastructure and Transportation: Our Nation at a Crossroads," (Editorial), The Bridge, Vol. 38, No. 2, Summer 2008, pp. 3-4., 2008 Summer (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - #310 – Bugliarello, G., "Water: Advances in the Supply and Management of a Vital Resource," (Editorial), The Bridge, Vol. 38, No. 3, Fall 2008, pp. 3-4., 2008 Fall (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - #311 – Bugliarello, G., "Biomedical Engineering Ethics: Specificity versus The Absolute," International Journal of Medical Implants and Devices, Vol. 3, No. 2, 2008, pp. 75-80. (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - #312 – Bugliarello, G., "Science, Technology and Society: The Tightening Circle," in Science and Technology and the Future Development of Societies, International Workshop Proceedings, G. Schweitzer (Ed.), National Academies Press, Washington, DC, 2008. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - #313 – Bugliarello, G., "A Note on the Interfacial Vulnerabilities of Transportation Systems," in Countering Terrorism: Biological Agents, Transportation Networks, and Energy Systems, Summary of a U.S.-Russian Workshop, Committee on Counterterrorism Challenges for Russia and the United States, The National Academies Press, Washington, DC, 2009. (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - #314 – Bugliarello, G., "Mechanics, Biology and Medicine and The Challenges of Metamechanics: A Personal Reflection," Keynote Address, 16th International Conference on Mechanics in Medicine and Biology, University of Pittsburgh, July 23-25, 2008 (accepted for publication, Journal of Mechanics and Medicine in Biology)., 2009 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - #315 – Bugliarello, G., "Reflections on Morality, Ethics, and Bioethics Decisions," Journal of Long-Term Effects of Medical Implants, Vol. 18, No. 1, 2008, pp. 85-90. (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - #316 – Bugliarello, G., "Engineering for an Aging World Population," (Editorial), The Bridge, Vol. 39, No. 1, Spring 2009, pp. 3-4., 2009 Spring (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - #317 – Bugliarello, G., "Megacities: Four Major Questions," Journal of Urban Technology, Vol. 16, No. 1, 2009, pp. 151-160. (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - #318 – Bugliarello, G., "Engineering: Emerging and Future Challenges," in Engineering: Issues and Challenges and Opportunities for Development, a report of UNESCO in conjunction with The World Federation of Engineering Organizations and the International Council of Academies of Engineering and Technological Sciences (CAETS), UNESCO Publishing, 2010. (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - #319 – Bugliarello, G., "Engineering, Technology and Society," in Engineering: Issues Challenges and Opportunities for Development, a report of UNESCO in conjunction with The World Federation of Engineering Organizations and the International Council of Academies of Engineering and Technological Sciences (CAETS), UNESCO Publishing, 2010. (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - #319a – Bugliarello, G., "Editor's Note: Nuclear Dangers" – The Bridge, Vol. 40, No. 2 – Summer 2010, 2010 Summer (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - #320 – Bugliarello, G., "Ethics of Medicine, Biology and Bioengineering at the New Critical Crossroads for Our Species - Beyond Aristotle and Hippocrates," Ethics in Biology, Engineering and Medicine, Vol. 1, Issue 1, 2010, pp. 3-8. (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - #321 – Bugliarello, G., "Introduction to Don Alstadt's Book," November 26, 2008, 2008 November 26 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - #322 – Bugliarello, G., "The Future of Urban Sustainability: Some Urgent Sociotechnological Challenges," Sustainability: The Journal of Record, Vol. 3, No. 6, December 2010, 2010 December (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - #323 – Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and Sustainable Development: Fostering Technology, Innovation and Production," in ISTIC-UNESCO-WFEO Workshop on Science, Engineering and Industry: Innovation for Sustainable Development (P. Bereciartua and G.A. Lemarchand (eds.), UNESCO, 2011. (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - #324 – Bugliarello, G., "Perspectives on Urban Sustainability," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 41, No. 1, Spring 2011., 2011 Spring (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - #325 - Bugliarello, G., "Critical New Bio-Socio-Technological Challenges in Urban Sustainability," Journal of Urban Technology, Vol. 18, No. 3, July 2011, pp. 3-23., 2011 July (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - #326 - Bugliarello, G., "Reflections on Durability, Sustainability and the Quest for a Basic Science of Sustainability," in editorial preparation for anticipated publication in Technology in Society, Vol. 33. No. 3, September 2011., 2011 September (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - #327 - Bugliarello, G., "Global Health Care Delivery: a Pandora's Box of Ethical Issues," Ethics in Biology, Engineering & Medicine- An International Journal, 2(1): 71-76 (2011) (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Publications – Unidentified, Undated (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - M9 - Bugliarello, G., "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Man, Society and Machines," Chief Executive Magazine, No. 5, July 1978, 1978 July (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - M15 - Bugliarello, G., "Il Parco Tecnologico: Note Sulle Risorse, Competenze ed Organizzazione," In Innovare Il Polo Tecnologico di Napoli, Volume 3, SIPI, Rome, 1991. (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - M16 - Bugliarello, G., A review of Noise and Health (edited by Thomas H. Fay. New York: The New York Academy of Medicine, 1991). May 1992., 1992 November (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - M22a - Bugliarello, G., Comment in "Responses to the Laws of "STS" and the Laws of Science, Bulletin of Science, Technology and Society, Vol. 15, No. 1, pp. 3-4, 1995. (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - MS2 - Bugliarello, G., Stackhouse, John, "Science," Humankind Advancing, Vol. 12, No. 3, July 2001., 2001 July (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - MS3 - Bugliarello, G., "Transforming Urban Blight into Brooklyn's 'Wall Street East'," Research Park Forum, Association of University Related Research Parks, September 2000., 2000 September (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - N16 - Bugliarello, G., "Persian Gulf Area Can Be Rebuilt," The Reporter Dispatch, April 5, 1991., 1991 April 5 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - N18 - Bugliarello, G., "The Debate Over Academe's Ties With Industry," The Chronicle of Higher Education, letter to the editor, October 21, 1992., 1992 October (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering: Issues Challenges and Opportunities for Development," UNESCO Report, 2010. (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - Subseries B: Publication Original Copies
    - Publications – Original Copies- 1-17, 1953-1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 18-39, 1962-1966 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 40-59, 1966-1971 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 60-77, 1969-1970 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 78-94, 1969-1970 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 95-106, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 107-124, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 125-145, 1975-1980 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 146-160, 1980-1984 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Publications – Original Copies- 161-177, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 178 – 189, 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 190 – 216, 1987-1991 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 217 – 235, 1991-1995 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 236- 259, 1994-1999 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 260-284, 1999-2003 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 285-306, 2003-2007 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Publications – Original Copies – 307-327, 2007-2011 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Subseries C: Manuscripts
    - Socio-Technology – Binder #1 – 1, Undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Socio-Technology – Binder #1 – 2, Undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Socio-Technology – Binder #1 – 3, Undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - George Bugliarello Membership – Binder # 1 – 1, Undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - George Bugliarello Membership – Binder # 1 – 2, Undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - George Bugliarello Membership – Binder # 1 – 3, Undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - George Bugliarello Membership – Binder # 1 – 4, Undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Socio-Technology – Binder #2 – 1, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Socio-Technology – Binder #2 – 2, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Technology & Merchandising - Binder #1 - 1, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Technology & Merchandising - Binder #1 - 2, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Photocopies of Business cards, Undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - "Computers and Water Resources" – Part 1, Undated (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - "Computers and Water Resources" – Part 2, Undated (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Publication Compilation - 1, Undated (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Publication Compilation - 2, Undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Publication Compilation - 3, Undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Publication Compilation - 4, Undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Publication Compilation - 5, Undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Publication Compilation - 6, Undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Subseries D: Biosoma
    Biosoma, a term coined by George Bugliarello, refers to the interaction between biology, society and machines. This subseries contains manuscripts, publications, drafts, notes, and research materials relating to George Bugliarello's research and promotion of the Biosoma paradigm.
    - Article - "Biology, Machines and Society: Designing the Future of Our Species" Presentation – Transparencies, Undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Article - "Biosoma Engineering" – Drafts, 2010 December- 2011 January (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Article - "The Biosoma Paradigm for Earth Systems Engineering", 2004 March - 2005 November (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Article - "The Biosoma Paradigm and Environmental Engineering" – Proofs, Published Copy, 2007 January, March (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Article - "The Biosoma Paradigm and Environmental Engineering" – Submission, 2004 September - 2007 May (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Article - "The Biosoma: The Symbiosis of Man, Society and Machine", 1979 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Article - "The Biosoma: The Symbiosis of Man, Society and Machine" – Draft, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Article - "The Biosoma: The Synthesis of Biology, Machines, and Society" – Edits – Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, 2000 December (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Article - "For a Human Future: Reflections on the Synthesis of Biology, Society and Machines (The Biosoma)", 2000 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Article - "Reflections on Machines and the Synthesis of Biological Organisms, Society and Machines" – Revised Texts, 1999 November 11 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Article - "Reflections on Machines" – Drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Article - "Reflections on Machines" – Presentations, Undated (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Biosoma Design, 2010-2012 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Book Mailings, 2003 April - 2005 June (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Draft – "June 20 Version", Undated (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Drafts, Undated (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Drafts, Transparencies, 1998 September (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Figures, Undated (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Final Publication, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Franz J. Gayl, 2005 February (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Harmony Books Publisher, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Internet Submission, 1999 June - 2000 July (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Internet Submission, 2000 October - 2005 April (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Machine Figures – Revisions, 1997 January 21 (Box 34, Folder 28)
    - Manuscript, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript – 1, 1999 August (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript – 2, 1999 August (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript - "Engineering for a Better Human Future: Reflections on the Synthesis of Biology, Society and Machines (The Biosoma)" - 2000 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript - "For a Human Future: Reflections on the Synthesis of Biology, Society and Machines (The Biosoma)", 2000 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1999 September - 2004 July (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 2005 April-June, Undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous – Manuscript Drafts, 1988-1989, Undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous – Manuscript Drafts - Notes, Undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous - Presentations, Copies, Undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous – Presentations, 1996, Undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - New Graphics, 1998 February, 1999 June-July (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Outlines & Notes, Undated (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Presentation – Long Version, 1998 September 4 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Presentation copies & transparencies – "Designing the Future of our Species", Undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Presentations, 1996 April (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Principles of Biosoma Design, 2010 December 9 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Reviews & Reviewer Correspondence, 1979 May - 1988 November (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Revision – Terry Bristol – 1, 1999 August (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Revision – Terry Bristol – 2, 1999 August (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - The New Press, 2001 February-June (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Time Scale, Undated (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - University Press of America, 2004 August 31 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - University Press of America, 2007 June-July (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Subseries E: Technology and Society
    This subseries contains mostly correspondence and memoranda relating to the publication of Technology in Society, a journal founded and co-edited by George Bugliarello along with Polytechnic professor A. George Schillinger. Technology and Society is an international journal focused on the role of technology in society and its influence on economics, political and cultural dynamics.
    - 25th Anniversary Issue, 2004 April-August (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence – E-F, 1984-2001 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - G-H, 1984-1997 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence – O-P, 1985-1999 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence – Q-R, 1984-2002 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1998-2006, 1998 January - 2006 February (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 2011, 2011 July 15 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Editorial, Acknowledgement, 1997 April 30 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Elsevier Science – Correspondence, 1995 February - 1996 June, 2002 July (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Elsevier Science - 2009-2010, 2009 October - 2010 February (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Elsevier Science Meeting, 2010 May-November (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Military Issue, 2000 August, 2001 February (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous - 2005 January (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous - 2008-2009 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous 2008-2010 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous - 2009-2010 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous - 2010 May-September (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous - 2010 May-November (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - New Journal, 2010 January - 2011 February (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Pergamon Press, Inc., 1986-1993 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Press Luncheon, 2004 May-July (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Proceedings, Ads, Publishers, 1985 November - 1987 September (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Barry Rosenblatt, 1992 January-November (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Harold P. Sjursen - Editor, 2010 March-September (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Special Issue – Volume 19, No. 2-3, 1997, 1996-1997 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Subseries F: Miscellaneous
    - "The 1983 DOE University Programs Panel Report: A University Perspective" - Forging New Engineering Partnerships Conference Proceedings – Midwest Universities Energy Consortium, 1993 November 4-5 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Articles - Miscellaneous - 1981-1997 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Articles and Speeches - Miscellaneous - 1985-1989 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Articles - Miscellaneous - 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Articles - Miscellaneous - 1990-1991 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Articles - Miscellaneous - 1997 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Articles - Miscellaneous - 2000-2001, 2000 February - 2001 October (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - "Bioengineering Ethics: Complexity and Synthesis" – International Journal of Medical Implants and Devices – Volume 1, No. 2, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - "Education for the Changing Pace of Technology: The Need to Transcend our Self-Imposed Boundaries" – Education for the Changing Pace of Technology – Volume 1, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - "Emerging and Future Areas of Engineering" – U.N.E.S.C.O. Report "Engineering Issues, Challenges and Opportunities for Development", 2010 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - "Engineering and Sustainable Development: Fostering Technology Innovation and Production" – U.N.E.S.C.O. Workshop on Science, Engineering and Industry: Innovation for Sustainable Development, 2011 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - "The Engineering Challenges of Urban Sustainability" – Journal of Urban Technology – Volume 15, No. 1, 2008 April (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - "Ethics of Medicine, Biology and Bioengineering at the New Critical Crossroads for our Species – Beyond Aristotle and Hippocrates" – Ethics in Biology, Engineering & Medicine – Volume 1, Issue 1, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 3)